Oppenheimer and his team had done the
impossible and they were now ready to
test launch the world's first ever
nuclear bomb set to take place in the
open desert plains of New Mexico
Oppenheimer would name the event Trinity
with over 400 people coming to witness
the dawn of a new age and so in the
early hours of July 16th 1945 the
goahead to detonate the bomb was given
the United States and the world had now
entered the atomic age but still
questions remained over how the bombs
were to be used was it moral to use the
bomb should it be used against strictly
military targets or should civilian
areas also be considered these were not
the questions for scientists and
Engineers who had built the bomb however
but rather for the politicians in
Washington and in particular the United
States's new commanderin-chief Harry